<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on My Site</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on My Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Animal Movement and Behaviour</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/2023-11-09-animal-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/2023-11-09-animal-movement/</guid>
      <description>During the Phd, I came across Movebank which is a huge online database for animal tracking data. This type of data, generally gather through a GPS device attached to an animal, which record its coordinate at fixed time point.
Such data can be used to understand animal behaviour and how they move through space. There is a rich litaruture on the topic, and if you are itnerested you can read the book of Hooten et al.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From R to Julia</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/topic/2023-11-02-from-r-to-julia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/topic/2023-11-02-from-r-to-julia/</guid>
      <description>I love programming and R is a fantastic language for statisticians. It&amp;rsquo;s super flexible and great for data treatment. R has a lot of great qualities, but speed isn&amp;rsquo;t one of them, which can be a problem if you&amp;rsquo;re a Bayesians dealing with complex models. I used to call C++ inside R code to speed things up, so I could do all the initial data handling in R, and then let C++ do the real computation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Describing myself is never easy, but here goes: I&amp;rsquo;m a Statistician who&amp;rsquo;s really into Bayesian statistics, particularly from an applied problem-solving and implementation perspective. I work as an associate professor at the Polytechnic of Turin, in the Department of Mathematical Sciences. If you&amp;rsquo;re curious about my research, check out my (my institutional webpage), my Arxiv, or my github page, where you can also find codes related to my published papers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My CV</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/cv/</guid>
      <description>WORK IN PROGRESS Selected Papers (November 2023) Donatelli, Aurora; Mastrantonio, Gianluca; Ciucci, Paolo (2022). Circadian activity of small brown bear populations living in human-dominated landscapes. In: SCIENTIFIC REPORTS, vol. 12. ISSN 2045-2322
Mastrantonio, Gianluca (2022) Modeling animal movement with directional persistence and attractive points. In: THE ANNALS OF APPLIED STATISTICS, vol. 16. ISSN 1932-6157
Mastrantonio, Gianluca (2022) The modelling of movement of multiple animals that share behavioural features. In: JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL STATISTICAL SOCIETY SERIES C-APPLIED STATISTICS.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
